American Psychological Association Records
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Boards and Committees, 1920-1986 (Box 292-549)
  - Continuing committees
    - Committee on Psychology in Medical Schools, 1970
    - Committee on Psychology in the Secondary Schools
      - Correspondence
        - Drafts of ethical principles, 1976-1978
        - General, 1976-1978, undated (Box 494)
        - Participants, 1975-1977
      - Evaluation of ethical principles in teaching, 1978
      - Minutes, 1977
      - Miscellany, 1976-1977
      - Reports, 1974-1978
    - Committee on Publications, correspondence regarding the Meier resolution, 1948-1950
    - Committee on Public Relations
      - Articles and papers, 1950-1957, undated
      - Correspondence, 1939, 1946-1958, undated, (4 folders) (Box 495)
      - Minutes and agenda, 1953-1954
      - Miscellany, undated
      - Reports, 1947-1957
    - Committee on Questionnaires, 1951-1957, undated, (2 folders)
    - Committee on Relations with American Speech and Hearing Association, 1954-1958
    - Committee on Relations with Psychiatry
      - Articles and newsletters, 1954-1960
      - Correspondence (Box 496)
        - General
          - 1945-1955, (7 folders)
          - 1956-1966, undated, (8 folders) (Box 497)
        - Regarding legislation, 1955, 1958, undated (Box 498)
        - To Doctor Sanford, 1954-1955
      - Legislation
        - Addenda, acts and bills, undated
        - Reports, 1955-1959, 1965, undated
      - Minutes, 1953-1954, 1965-1966
      - Miscellany, 1954-1956, 1966
      - Reports
        - General, 1950-1960
        - Position statements, 1963-1966, undated
    - Committee on Relations with the Social Work Profession (Box 499)
      - Correspondence, 1947-1956, (2 folders)
      - Meetings, agenda, and miscellany, 1951-1954, undated
      - Reports, 1948-1955
    - Committee on Relations with Sociology, 1958-1959
    - Committee on Relationship Between Psychology and Religion, 1958-1959
    - Committee on Retired Psychologists, 1954-1964, (2 folders)
    - Committee on Scientific and Professional Ethics and Conduct, 1962-1966, undated, (2 folders)
    - Committee on Scientific and Professional Responsibility, 1961 (Box 500)
    - Committee on Social Controls, 1955-1956
    - Committee on Social Science in Public Health, 1954-1957, undated, (2 folders)
    - Committee on Social Utilization of Unemployed Psychologists, 1935-1936, undated, (2 folders)
    - Committee on Standards for Providers of Psychological Services
      - Correspondence, 9 July 1979
      - Drafts
        - Specialty guidelines, unnumbered, 31 Jan. 1980
        - Standards, nos. 6, 8, 9, and unnumbered, 1979
    - Committee on Standards for Psychological Service Centers
      - 1946-1947
      - 1948-1951 (Box 501)
    - Committee on State Examination Procedures, 1947-1950, 1958-1962, undated, (2 folders)
    - Committee on State Legislation
      - Correspondence, 1955-1959, 1967-1971, 1976, undated, (6 folders)
      - Minutes, 1959, 1969-1970
      - Miscellany, 1956-1960, 1968-1970 (Box 502)
      - Reports
        - Drafts of 1975-1977, undated
        - General, 1955-1959, 1967-1970
    - Committee on Structure and Function of Council
      - Agenda
        - 1970-1977, (3 folders)
        - 1978-1979, (2 folders) (Box 503)
      - Annual reports, 1967-1976
      - Articles, 1969-1977
      - Correspondence
        - Drafts of letters, 1970-1974, undated
        - General
          - 1968-1972, (3 folders)
          - 1973-1979, undated, (5 folders) (Box 504)
      - Liaison program
        - Correspondence
          - 1970-1975
          - 1976-1980 (Box 505)
        - Functions of boards and members, undated
        - Lists, 1973-1980, undated
        - Preference assignments, 1973-1980, (3 folders)
        - Preference sheets, 1973-1976
      - Minutes, 1970-1979, undated (Box 506)
      - Miscellany, 1970-1977
      - Reports, undated
      - Subject file
        - Orientation meeting/new members
          - Agenda and related material, 1972-1979
          - Correspondence, 1972-1979, (2 folders)
          - Lists, 1972-1976
        - Task force on Nominations for Boards and Committees
          - Bylaws, APA, undated
          - Correspondence, 1973-1977
          - Miscellany, 1974
          - Reports, minutes, and related material, 1976-1977
          - Surveys and related material, 1976-1978
    - Committee on Student Affiliates, 1945-1952 (Box 507)
    - Committee on Teaching of Psychology in High Schools, 1951-1956
    - Committee on Testing Standards, 1950-1957, (2 folders)
    - Committee on the Fourteenth International Congress of Psychology, 1953-1954, (2 folders)
    - Committee on the Practice of Clinical Psychology (Box 508)
      - Agenda and minutes, 1963-1964
      - Correspondence, 1962-1966, (3 folders)
      - First meeting, 22 Oct. 1962
      - Reports, surveys, and related material, 1962-1964
    - Committee on the Relationship Between Psychology and the Clergy, 1954-1955
    - Committee on the Relationship Between Psychology and Education
      - Correspondence
        - Mar. 1954-Dec. 1956, (3 folders)
        - Jan. 1957-June 1958 (Box 509)
        - July 1958-May 1959, (5 folders) (Box 510)
        - June 1959-May 1964, (3 folders) (Box 511)
      - Minutes, 1955-1959
      - Miscellany, 1955-1960
      - Reports and surveys
        - 1954-1958, (3 folders)
        - 1959, 1961, undated, (2 folders) (Box 512)
    - Committee on the Twelfth International Congress of Psychology, 1946-1948
    - Committee on the Walter V. Bingham Lectureship
      - Correspondence
        - 1953-1955, (3 folders)
        - 1956-1965, (2 folders) (Box 513)
    - Committee on Training in Clinical Psychology
      - Ballots, 1949
      - Boulder, Colo. conference
        - Correspondence, 1948-1951, (2 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1949-1951 (Box 514)
        - Publications, 1949-1950
        - Reports, undated
      - Correspondence
        - General
          - Jan. 1947-Dec. 1948, (5 folders)
          - Jan. 1949-July 1950, (6 folders) (Box 515)
          - Aug. 1950-Dec. 1951, undated, (5 folders) (Box 516)
        - Regarding meetings, 1947-1948
      - Financial matters
        - Budget, 1950-1951
        - Correspondence, regarding expense account and expenses, 1947-1950
        - Expenditures and related material, 1947-1951
        - Expense account information, 1948-1951
      - Minutes and agenda, 1947-1950 (Box 517)
      - Miscellany, 1948-1949, undated
      - Reports, 1947-1951, undated, (2 folders)
      - Subject file
        - Evaluations, 1949
        - Filing system, 1950-1951
        - Legislation
          - Acts and bills, 1946-1949, undated
          - Correspondence, 1948-1951, 1982, undated (Box 518)
          - Miscellany, 1949, undated
        - Objective criteria, 1950
    - Committee on Undergraduate Education
      - Articles and papers, 1958, 1976-1978, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence
        - May 1952-May 1977, (2 folders)
        - June 1977-Oct. 1979, undated, (7 folders) (Box 519)
      - Minutes, 1977-1978
      - Miscellaneous material, 1972-1978, undated
      - Reports, 1952-1958 (Box 520)
      - Surveys and results, 1978
    - Committee on Women and Health
      - Correspondence, 1978-1983, undated, (6 folders)
      - Minutes, 1978-1982
      - Miscellany, undated (Box 521)
      - Nominations for National Institutes of Health, 1980
      - Reports, articles and papers, 1980-1982
    - Committee on Women in Psychology
      - Agenda, 1973-1975, (4 folders)
      - Articles and related material, 1969-1973, undated (Box 522)
      - Correspondence
        - 1965, 1970-1974, (6 folders)
        - 1975-1976, undated, (4 folders) (Box 523)
      - Minutes, 1973-1975
      - Miscellany, 1970-1975, undated, (2 folders)
      - Reports, 1973-1974, undated
    - Committee to Draft a Proposal for an APA Statistical-Methodological Journal (Box 524)
      - Agenda and reports, 1975-1979
      - Correspondence, 1975-1981, (2 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1973, 1978, undated
    - Committee to Review the Testimony of Ralph Grundlach
      - Correspondence, 1949-1955, undated, (2 folders)
      - Reports, 1951-1952
    - Elections Committee, 1957, undated
    - House Committee, 1952-1961, undated, (2 folders)
    - Investigating Committee on Veterans Administration Reclassification
      - Correspondence
        - Mar.-Apr. 1950
        - May-Dec. 1950, (2 folders) (Box 525)
      - Reports, 1950
    - Library Committee, 1953-1954, (2 folders)
    - National Committee for Federation and Affiliation of Applied Psychology, 1936-1937
    - National Advisory Council on Radio in Education, 1930-1937, undated, (2 folders)
    - Nominating Committee for Executive Secretaryship (Box 526)
      - Ballots, June 1950
      - Correspondence, 1950
    - Planning Committee for the Conference on the Evaluation of Behavior, 1953-1957
    - Planning Committee on APA Conference on Research of Psychological Aspects of Rehabilitation Conference
      - Correspondence, 1957-1960, undated
      - Miscellany, 1956-1960, undated
      - Reports and drafts, 1957-1960, undated
    - Public Information Committee, 1982, undated
    - Scientific Development Board, 1954-1956
  - Joint committees (Box 527)
    - Accreditation of Hospitals - Accreditation Council for services to the Mentally Retarded and Developmentally Disabled Persons
      - Agenda, 1978
      - Correspondence, 1969-1978, (2 folders)
      - Memoranda, 1973-1978, (3 folders)
      - Miscellany and related material, 1967-1978
      - Nominations, 1979 (Box 528)
      - Officers' election, 1973
    - American Public Health Association Committee on Public Health and Behavioral Sciences, 1957-1963, (2 folders)
    - On Child and Adolescent Psychology in the Education of Psychologists, 1961-1965, (3 folders)
    - On Revision of Test Standards
      - Agenda, 1972-1983, (4 folders)
      - Correspondence (Box 529)
        - Advisors' comments
          - General, 1981-1983
          - On third draft, 1971-1973
          - On 1983 draft
            - Angoff, William, 1983
            - "A-B" miscellaneous, 1983-1984
            - Comments, digest of, 1983 (Box 530)
            - "C-R" miscellaneous, 1983-1984, (4 folders)
            - "S-Z" miscellaneous, 1983-1984 (Box 531)
          - On fourth draft, comments, digest of, Jan.-July 1984, (4 folders)
        - Committee members (Box 532)
          - From, 1977-1979
          - With, 1980-1983, undated, (4 folders)
        - Committee nominees, 1978-1981
        - Funding, 1980-1981
        - General
          - Apr. 1971-Dec. 1977
          - Jan. 1978-June 1982, (6 folders) (Box 533)
          - July 1982-Dec. 1984, undated, (4 folders) (Box 534)
        - Requests for information, 1979, undated
        - With advisors, 1981-1983
        - With organizations, 1981-1982
      - Financial information, budget (Box 535)
        - Annual, 1981
        - General, 1981-1984, (4 folders)
        - Proposals, 1981
        - Financial check requests, 1981-1984
          - "A-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
          - Special project - Ohio
        - Grant expenses, 1981-1982
          - Hotel expenses, 1983-1985
          - Iowa expenses, 1981-1982 (Box 536)
          - Printing, 1981-1985
          - Related material, 1981-1983
          - Telephone expenses, 1981-1984
          - Travel expenses, 1981-1984, (4 folders)
      - Memoranda
        - General, 1982-1984
        - Novick, 1980-1981
        - O'Bryant, 1981-1982 (Box 537)
        - Soule, 1980-1981
      - Minutes and notes
        - General, 1971-1983, (7 folders)
        - Standards, draft of 1983
      - Miscellany
        - 1973-1977
        - 1980-1984, undated, (2 folders) (Box 538)
      - Reports, 1978-1980
      - Standards
        - Drafts
          - 1981-1982
          - 1983 (Box 539)
          - Miscellany, 1983
          - Third draft and 31⁄2, 1973
      - Subject file
        - Background material, 1981
        - Ballot by reviews, 1973 (Box 540)
        - Candidates for Barbara Pedulla's replacement, 1978-1981, undated
        - Comments from Test Publishers, 1977
        - Funding Proposals, 1982
        - Legal review of Standards, 1982
        - Members' vitae, 1978-1981
        - Relations between psychology and education, 1986
        - Review material, 1981
        - Russell Sage Foundation, 1973, 1980-1985
        - Standards prior years (Box 541)
          - Orders lists and miscellany, 1979-1986
          - Test manuals, 1980, undated
        - Tallies, undated, (2 folders)
        - Test sponsor's meeting, Oct. 1982
        - Uniform guidelines, 1976-1981
    - To Study the Relationships of Medicine with Allied Health Professions and Services
      - Agenda, 19 Mar. 1960, (2 folders)
      - Proceedings, 1959-1960, (4 folders) (Box 542)
      - Report, 1960
  - Commissions (Box 543)
    - Accelerating Black Participation
      - Articles, 1968-1969
      - Correspondence, 1968-1970, undated
      - Minutes, 1969
      - Miscellany, 1969-1970
      - Reports and statements, 1969-1970, undated
    - Accreditation of APA, 1969
    - Behavior Modification, 1977
    - Composition of Council
      - Articles, 1959, 1965-1967, undated
      - Background, 1957, 1959, 1965-1967
      - Correspondence
        - Drafts of letters, undated
        - General
          - Jan.-July 1966
          - Aug. 1966-Nov. 1967, undated, (6 folders) (Box 544)
      - Drafts, critiques, 1966-1967, undated, (2 folders)
      - Minutes, 1966-1967 (Box 545)
      - Miscellany, 1966-1967, undated, (2 folders)
      - Reports
        - Drafts of, 1966, (2 folders)
        - General, 1966-1967, undated
    - Mechanisms
      - Correspondence, 1970-1972
      - Minutes and agenda, 1969, 1971 (Box 546)
      - Miscellany, 1970-1971, undated, (2 folders)
      - Reports and papers, 1971, undated
    - Organization of APA
      - Agenda, 1980
      - Briefing material
        - Oct. 1978-Jan. 1979, (4 folders)
        - July-Nov. 1979, (5 folders) (Box 547)
        - Feb. 1980, (1 folder) (Box 548)
        - June-Oct. 1980, (4 folders)
        - Mar. 1981, (1 folder) (Box 549)
      - Correspondence, 1979-1981
      - Miscellany, 1958, 1979-1981
      - Origins of commission, Apr. 1979
      - Report, 1980
    - Status of Women in the Southeast, 1967-1973, undated
  - Joint Commissions
    - On Accreditation of Hospitals, 1975-1980, (4 folders)
- Divisions, 1917-1985 (Box 550-620)
  Correspondence, memoranda, agenda, minutes of meetings, bylaws, reports, reviews, surveys, lists, applications, budget material, statements, financial material, notebooks, articles, handbooks, legal material, studies, papers, dissertations, surveys, and miscellaneous administration and informational data.
  Organized by division according to the number or designation given the material by the APA and therein alphabetically by subject or type of material. A miscellany file arranged alphabetically by type of material is at the end of the series.
  - Division 1: General Psychology (Box 550)
    - Bylaws
    - Correspondence, 1946-1950
  - Division 2: Teaching of Psychology
    - Behavioral Instruction: An Evaluative Review, 1976
    - Bylaws
    - Committees, 1975-1976
      - Election
      - Membership
      - Special Committee on Continuing Education
    - Correspondence, general, 1946-1954, (3 folders)
    - Fellowship applicants, 1974-1975
    - President's file
      - Agenda and related material, 1974-1976
      - Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 551)
      - Fellow applicants, 1974-1975
      - Minutes, 1976
      - Reports, 1975-1976
    - Psychology 101, 1969-1975
    - Publications, newsletters, 1950-1954
    - Report, 1951-1952
    - Standards for Providers of Psychological Services, 1974-1976
    - Teaching of Psychology
      - Editor search committee, 1976, 1982-1984
      - General, 1972-1976, 1982, (3 folders) (Box 552)
      - Survey, 1975
  - Division 3: Experimental Psychology (Box 553)
    - Bylaws
    - Correspondence, general, 1946-1954, (2 folders)
    - Meeting, 1966
  - Division 5: Evaluation and Measurement
    - Bylaws, 1946, 1962
    - Committees
      - Computer Programs, 1959-1963
      - Executive, 1963-1966
      - General, 1963-1966
      - Membership, 1960-1963
      - Program, 1961-1963 (Box 554)
      - Test Review, 1958-1963
    - Correspondence, general, 1946-1966, (3 folders)
    - Expenses for meeting, 1965-1966
    - Meetings, business, 1946-1948, 1960-1965
    - Membership applications, 1962-1963, (2 folders)
    - Officers' handbook, 1958
    - President, 1961-1962 (Box 555)
    - Secretary, 1962-1964
    - Visiting psychologists, 1962-1963
  - Division 6: Physiological and Comparative Psychology
    - Bylaws, 1961-1962
    - Correspondence, general, 1946-1948, 1960-1962, 1973-1977, (2 folders)
  - Division 7: Developmental Psychology
    - Annual records/reports
      - 1945-1959, (3 folders)
      - 1960-1979, (4 folders) (Box 556)
    - Bylaws, 1946-1979 (Box 557)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1946-1954, (2 folders)
      - Related to G. Stanley Hall, 1980-1983
    - Inventory and newsletter, 1982-1983
  - Division 8: Personality and Social Psychology
    - Behavioral science laboratory, 1977-1979
    - Budget, 1977-1980, (3 folders)
    - Bylaws (Box 558)
      - General, 1946-1978
      - Petition for revision, 1979
    - Committees
      - Executive
        - 1975
        - 1978-1979
      - Fellowship, 1977-1979
      - Membership, 1975-1980
      - Personality, 1976-1979
      - Publications, 1977-1980, (3 folders)
      - Subcommittee on Personality & Division Structure, 1979
    - Correspondence, general (Box 559)
      - 1946-1953, 1976-1979, (5 folders)
    - Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 1977-1978
    - Meetings
      - Annual
        - 1977
        - 1978-1979, (2 folders) (Box 560)
      - Spring, 1979
    - Officer nominations, 1977-1979
    - Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin, 1974-1980, (3 folders)
    - Research Academic Coalition, 1978-1979 (Box 561)
    - Workshops, 1976-1978
  - Division 9: Society for Psychological Study of Social Issues
    - Bylaws, undated
    - Dues, 1966-1967
    - General correspondence, 1941-1954, (5 folders)
    - Newsletter, 1962
  - Division 10: Psychology and the Arts
    - Bylaws, undated
    - Correspondence, general, 1946-1954, (2 folders) (Box 562)
  - Division 12: Clinical Psychology
    - Agenda, 1966-1967
    - Bylaws, 1940, 1946-1967
    - Committees
      - Awards, 1961-1963
      - Corresponding Committee of 50, 1961-1963
      - Defining Clinical Psychology, 1962
      - Executive
        - General, 1960
        - Meeting, Denver, Colo., March 1961
        - Minutes, 1960-1961
      - Insurance, 1961-1963
      - Interdivisional relations, 1959 (Box 563)
      - Interprofessional relations, 1947-1950
      - Issues in the Training of Clinical Psychologists, 1961-1963
      - Legislative, 1951-1952
      - Membership, 1961
      - Miscellany, 1966-1967
      - Officers, 1960-1961 (Box 564)
      - Post-Doctoral Institute, 1961-1967
      - Private Practice, 1961-1963
      - Program, 1959-1961, 1966
      - Relations Between Division 12 and Local Organizations, 1961-1963
    - Correspondence, general
      - 1930-1937, 1946-1947, (4 folders)
      - 1948-1954, (8 folders) (Box 565)
      - 1960-1976, (2 folders) (Box 566)
    - Miscellany, 1958-1960
    - Newsletters
      - General, 1966-1967, 1975
      - Miscellaneous, 1947-1953, (2 folders)
    - President's file
      - General
        - 1964-1966
        - 1967-1968 (Box 567)
      - New York trip, 1965-1966
    - Reports
      - Ad Hoc Committee, undated
      - Miscellaneous, 1947-1953, 1966
    - Subject file
      - Bibliography, annotated, 1956
      - Boulder, Colo. conference, 1949
      - Central Office Manual, 1959
      - Child section, 1963-1966 (Box 568)
      - Clinical Psychologist
        - Articles regarding, 1963-1964
        - General, 1982
      - Clinical Psychology Division, sections, 1966-1967
      - Education and Training Board, 1962-1963
      - Expression, emotional interpretation of, 1925-1926
      - Extrasensory perception, 1936-1937
      - Information from division secretary, 1945-1946
      - Insurance issue, 1961
      - Minutes, miscellaneous, 1917-1934
      - Officers and committee members, 1966-1967
      - Officers' handbook, 1958
      - Request for legislative information, by state, 1951-1952 (Box 569)
      - Reorganization, 1961-1962
      - Veterans Administration dispute in New York, N.Y., 1950
      - Wisconsin Psychiatric Institute, 1963
      - Workshop, 1959-1961
  - Division 13: Consulting Psychology
    - Bylaws, 1952
    - Committee on fellowship standards, 1961
    - Correspondence, general
      - 1946-1949
      - 1950-1954, (3 folders) (Box 570)
    - Publications, 1949-1966
  - Division 14: Industrial and Organizational Psychology
    - Administrative file, 1979-1980, (3 folders)
    - Bylaws, 1949-1952 (Box 571)
    - Committees
      - Committee on Committees, 1973
      - Executive Committee, 1978-1980
      - Long Range Planning, 1977
      - Professional Affairs, 1976-1978
      - Program Committee, 1976-1978
      - Standards for Providers of Psychological Services, 1979
      - Workshop Committee, 1980
    - Correspondence
      - Alphabetical
        - A-E, 1972-1975, (2 folders)
        - F-N, 1972-1975, (4 folders) (Box 572)
        - O-Z, 1972-1975, (3 folders) (Box 573)
      - Chronological
        - 1946-1949
        - 1950-1954, 1965, (2 folders) (Box 574)
      - Special
        - Tenopyr, Mary, 1977-1978
        - Thayer, Paul, 1977
    - Miscellany, 1948-1952 (Box 575)
    - Reports, 1980
    - Subject file
      - Amicus curiae
        - Brief, 1977
        - Orders, 1977
      - Cattell award
        - Account, 1972-1975
        - Disbursement funds, 1977-1979
        - Notebook entries, 1977-1980
        - Proposals
          - 1977-1978
          - 1979-1981, (3 folders) (Box 576)
      - Financial statements, 1973, 1978-1981 (Box 577)
      - Library of Congress transfer, 1982
      - Licensing and Industrial/Organizational Psychology, 1982
      - Meetings
        - APA, 1977
        - Executive Committee, 1977
      - Membership, 1979-1981
      - Principles
        - Comments, 1980
        - Orders, 1977-1981
        - Revision, 1978-1980 (Box 578)
      - Who Are the Industrial/Organizational Psychologists? 1982
  - Division 15: Educational Psychology
    - Bylaws, 1946-1953
    - Correspondence, general
      - 1946-1955, 1970, (4 folders)
      - 1971 (Box 579)
    - Meeting, 18-19 Mar. 1971
    - Stanford University, Stanford, Calif., 1970-1971
  - Division 16: School Psychology
    - Annual records
      - 1982-1983
        - Vol. 1, (3 folders)
        - Vol. 2 (Box 580)
      - 1983-1984
        - Vol. 1-2, (3 folders)
        - Vol. 3, (1 folder) (Box 581)
      - 1984-1985
        - Vol. 1
        - Vol. 2
    - Bylaws, 1949, 1952
    - Correspondence, general
      - 1946-1953, (2 folders)
    - Correspondence, general (Box 582)
      - 1954-1956
    - Meetings
      - Agenda and related material, 1983-1985, (5 folders)
      - Minutes, 1982
      - Miscellany, 1947-19555
      - TAMU (Texas A & M University, College Station, Tex.) Survey, 1983 (Box 583)
      - Work Conference on the Questions and Training of School Psychologists, 1953-1954
  - Division 17: Counseling Psychology
    - Annual Report to APA Board of Directors, 1955-1961
    - Bylaws, 1946-1950
    - Committees
      - Committee on
        - Bibliographic Service, 1955-1957
        - Committees, 1954-1956
        - Conference on Training in Counseling Psychology, 1962
        - Definition, 1955-1956
        - Divisional Functions, 1956-1960
        - Elections
          - 1954-1958